♪The night wind shakes off
the withered leaves♪
♪I open the window and gaze at the moon♪
♪Haze spreads across the river,
lanterns drifting♪
♪I hear the memories rustling♪
♪Garden flowers shed petals one by one♪
♪Candlelight flickers,
swaying with melancholy♪
♪I sigh by the lamp over the long night♪
♪Past memories unfold scene by scene♪
♪It's all your face♪
♪Boldly trampling over my heart♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for love miswritten♪
♪And another for youth passed♪
♪With endless sorrow,
I once traced your silhouette♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for joy and sorrow♪
♪And another for parting and reunion♪
♪I write until splendor fades,
and I am no more♪
=Prelude of the White Snake=
=Episode 21=
Let's go.
Did I say I forgive you?
Now you're leaving?
Weren't you using me for the trial?
If you leave like this,
how do I avenge my parents?
Have you found your evil self?
What if that evil demon
comes back for revenge?
What if she doesn't find you
and harms the townspeople instead?
Since you need me for your trial,
then I'll use you once too.
I need to find your evil self
and catch the evil demon behind her.
Since she found you once,
she can find you again.
So I need you by my side
every single moment.
Without my permission,
you can't take one step away from me.
This all started because of you.
Shouldn't you see it through?
What if that evil demon
returns to do harm?
Can you really bear
to abandon everyone in the city?
to walk away like this?
Will you
pass your love trial or not?
♪Clumsy and new, we gave our first kiss♪
♪Never thought passionate eyes
would turn cold♪
♪I thought of pulling away,
but I'd barely begun♪
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I have questions,
I never questioned you♪
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
♪After all, I'm the one you deny♪
♪Having ever loved♪
Are you still angry with me?
I get cold in the winter.
Will you hold me?
I will.
And I get hot in the summer.
Do you have a bamboo mat at home?
Yes.
I like spicy food.
Do you like it?
I can accept it.
If you accidentally bite me,
will I be poisoned?
I'm not venomous.
I'm not.
Actually, I would quite like to see you
swallow a piglet whole.
What?
Swallow a piglet whole?
I can't do that.
But I can swallow Xu Xian whole for you.
Want to see that?
You'd better swallow the piglet.
No, I'll swallow you.
- The piglet.
- No.
So it was Bai Suzhen's evil self
who instigated Changming
to slaughter the Rakshasa Bird clan
and used the mural world
to absorb demonic energy,
causing all of this, right?
So you lied to me before?
No, Master.
Bai Suzhen and her sister
are actually good demons.
They came to repay a kindness.
They haven't harmed any mortals.
I never said I would capture them.
Thank you, Master.
Fahai,
I looked into your mind.
Did you set up
the barrier array backward?
Master, actually,
my trip down the mountain...
It was complicated.
It's hard to explain.
You haven't been led
by the nose, have you?
What a disgrace to our sect!
Is the heavens trying
to doom Jinshan Temple?
But Master, I'm just a lay disciple.
Then why do you think
I favor you so much?
Definitely not because of my good looks.
Among all my disciples,
you have the purest and kindest nature,
and you're the most likely
to inherit my mantle.
Then hurry and ordain me, Master.
Let me tell you a story first.
Your evil self failed this time,
so she'll come back.
If our guess is right,
she'll definitely make another move.
We must be careful.
With you leaning on me,
I can't focus on drawing talismans.
Are you even listening to me?
I am.
This is a matter
of life and death for you.
Can you take it seriously?
You're so harsh.
I just want to cling to you
a bit longer.
I'm done drawing.
Really? Then play with me for a while.
You draw.
Qing is back. I'll go check on her.
Come back.
I'm suddenly thirsty.
I'll go get some water.
I'll get it for you.
I'm hungry.
I'll cook for you.
I'm feeling dizzy.
I'll go rest.
Let me massage your temples.
The Drake Demon King
is a thousand-year-old high demon
with immense demonic energy.
Back then, to seal him
in the forbidden grounds,
our founder exhausted
a century of cultivation
and passed away right here.
Master, I don't want you to die.
When did I say I was going to die?
But if he breaks out,
won't you die?
As long as I live,
the sealing spell won't break.
And as long as the seal holds,
I won't die.
That's a relief.
Master,
the one Bai Suzhen encountered
during the tribulation then
was the Drake Demon King, right?
Based on your analysis,
yes.
If Xu Xian finds out,
he'll come to the temple to kill him.
Tell Xu Xian this:
If the Drake Demon King
were easy to kill,
why would we seal him away instead?
Understood, Master.
Also, remind the White Snake
and the Green Snake
not to reveal their true forms at will
or use their spiritual power recklessly.
If they keep using
spiritual power at will,
bringing on rain
and making my back ache,
I will go and capture them myself.
Master, calm down.
Amitabha.
Thank you for your leniency.
I'm only letting it slide
because an immortal guided them.
Otherwise, I...
Don't be angry, Master.
Let me rub your shoulders.
Clumsy.
Not my shoulders, my back.
Go warn them quickly.
I'm worried that the evil self
might attack them at any moment.
A bit to the right.
Well, Master...
What else?
Could you help break the contract?
You made this mess,
so break it yourself.
Master, you're leaving me
totally helpless.
I'm leaving you helpless?
Did I teach you that?
I can break it for you,
but you must promise me one thing.
Name it, Master.
Without a letter from me,
you are not to return to Jinshan Temple.
Why? Jinshan Temple is my home.
Come sit down.
I will impart the teachings to you.
Won't you break the contract?
What teachings?
Whatever it is, come over first.
Hurry up.
You're too far.
Here, drink some water.
I'll guide your hand.
Suzhen, where did Fahai go?
What are you two doing?
Why is the mood so weird?
Qing, Suzhen is learning
to draw talismans.
Talismans?
Is this what you drew?
Qing, don't touch it.
I drew this Tiangang talisman
with great care.
Alright, with great care.
So is this for attack or defense?
An explosive one.
Why didn't you say so earlier?
You didn't ask earlier.
Y-You're mocking me.
That's for laughing at my talismans.
My lord,
I just found out some crucial news.
What is it?
♪I also gave my youth to someone♪
♪I must admit, you made the journey♪
♪When loving you
became instinct, what's left♪
♪Seals a fate too brutal to amend♪
♪Clumsy and new, we gave our first kiss♪
♪Never thought passionate eyes
would turn cold♪
♪I thought of pulling away,
but I'd barely begun♪
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I have questions,
I never questioned you♪
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
♪After all, I'm the one you deny♪
♪Having ever loved♪